Guide to the Thomas Parran Papers, 1892-1968 UA.90.F14
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Miscellaneous Bibliography, VII.
  - Wilder, Russell M. Enriched Flour and Enriched Bread: How it Started Nutrition Planning for the Nat. Defense (Box 52, Folder 905)
  - William, Maurice, D.D.S. Health Service and the Public, 1936 (Box 52, Folder 906)
  - Williams, R.C. Present Status of Proposed Torbidity Report Area, 1931 (Box 52, Folder 907)
  - Williams, Dr. W.C. "Looking Forward", 1939 (Box 52, Folder 908)
- Articles for Publication, 1923-1948; VIII.
  - Chest X-ray Statement by Dr. Parran to all Health Officers, February 16, 1948 (Box 52, Folder 909)
  - I Predict for 1948. Statement by Dr. Parran, Coronet Magazine, January 1948
  - Best Wishes Statement by Dr. Parran for final issue of Cadet Nurse Corps News, December, 1947
  - Public Health Nursing Week 1948. Statement by Dr. Parran, December 5, 1947
  - Chicago Association of Commerce and Industry. Telegram from Dr. Parran.on sponsoring "Medicine Looks Ahead" meeting, November 19, 1947
  - We could Banish V.D. in Nine Days by Dr. Parran. Woman's Home Companion, November 1947
  - Housing Officials, National Association of. Statewent by Dr. Parran, October 31, 1947
  - Statement by Dr. Parran for health Chairmen; of General Federation of Women's Clubs, October 1947
  - Better Health for Your Community. Article for Agenda Magazine, September 1947
  - Philadelphia Triple-X Tuberculosis Campaign. Statement by Dr. Parran, September 1947
  - Statement on Brucellosis for the Legislative Committee of Minnesota, August 25, 1947
  - Counter-spy, David Harding Broadcast Message from Dr. Parran, August 10, 1947
  - American Hospital Association. Suggested Statement by Dr. Parran for Mr. John H. Hayes, Pres., August 1947 (Box 52, Folder 910)
  - Wyoming Fly Control Campaign. Statement by Dr. Parran., June 9, 1947
  - American Druggist. Statement by Dr. Parran, June 1947
  - Immunization. Article by Dr. Parran for publication in American Magazine, June 1947
  - Don't Be Afraid of Your Doctor. Dr. Parran in the American Weekly, June 15, 1947
  - Cadet Nurse Corps News for June 1947. (4th birthday of the Corps)
  - Be Your Age. Metro. Life Ins. Co. short, May 13, 1947
  - Country Gentleman. Statement by Dr. Parran, May 1947
  - American College of Surgeons. Statement for Bulletin of, April 17, 1947
  - American Museum of Health. Statement by Dr. Parran, April 29, 1947
  - American Cancer Society, D.C. Division. Statement by Dr. Parran requested by Mr. Corcoran Thom, Jr., April 17, 1947
  - Present Opportunity, The. Article by Dr. Parran to accompany series Of type plans for hospitals, published in Architectural Record, March - April 1947
  - Enigma of Cancer. Statement by Dr. Parran for Modern Medicine, March 4, 1947
  - Heart Disease, Radio talk by Dr. Parran over Mutual Broadcasting System, February 10, 1947 (Box 52, Folder 911)
  - The National Hospital Program by Dr. Parran for The County Officer Official publication of National Association of County Officials, February 1947
  - The Health of the Nation, article by Dr. Parran. Appeared in January 1947 issue of National Parent-Teacher.
  - "Women's Club Number". Statement by Dr. Parran for Texas Fed. of Women's Clubs and Tex. State Health Dept, January 1947
  - Federal Aid for Municipal Hospitals. Published by League of Wisc. Municipalities in The Municipality, November 1946
  - The Heart and Its Ills by Dr. Parran. Published in Think, Vol. XII, No. 8, IBM publication, August 1946
  - Preface to Rural Health and Medical Care by Dr. Parran for Drs. Mott and Roemer, June 1946 (Box 52, Folder 912)
  - If America Had a 10 year Plan by Dr. Parran. Published in Everybody's Digest, June 1946
  - Foreword to Venereal Disease Control Today, Vonderlehr Heller, by Dr. Parran, March 1946
  - Distribution of Public Health Responsibilities Among State Agencies by Dr. Parran, published in State Government, February 1946
  - 1946 - A Healthier Year? By Thomas Parran, M.D. Look Magazine, January 8, 1946
  - Health is Everybody's Business by Dr. Thomas Parran for Bliven's book - now published, July 20, 1945 (Box 53, Folder 913)
  - The Local Community amp; the National Health by Dr. Parran appearing in October 1945 issue of The American City. (Box 53, Folder 914)
  - Public Health in the Reconversion Period by Dr. Parran. Article for October 1945 issue of the Am. Journal of Public Health. (Box 53, Folder 915)
  - The Cadet Nurse - Her Future by Surgeon Gen. Parran for magazine section, New York Times, May 13, 1945 (Box 53, Folder 916)
  - The Relationship of the U.S. Public Health Service American Municipalities. Prepared for Am. Municipal Assn. for use in League magazines, September 1944 (Box 53, Folder 917)
  - Comment on Fishing - Kelly Mason Advertising, Inc. (Box 53, Folder 918)
  - Nursing, War - to be published in Encyclopedia Britannica, Britannica Book of the Year, 1944 (Box 53, Folder 919)
  - Keep Well This Winter - Printed in "This Week", November 28, 1943 (Box 53, Folder 920)
  - American Magazine. To be published in, 1944 (Box 53, Folder 921)
  - How to Beat the Doctor Shortage. Published "This Week", 1943 (Box 53, Folder 922)
  - Your Health in Wartime - Published in "This Week" magazine (Box 53, Folder 923)
  - Enough Cadets For All Hospitals by Surgeon General Thomas Parran. Published in Hospitals, September 1943 (Box 53, Folder 924)
  - "Conquest of Hunger" In August issue of Parents Magazine, 1943
  - A Blueprint for the Conquest of Hunger. P.H.R, June 11, 1943
  - "Wanted: 65,000 Student Nurses" - to be published in Coronet, 1943 (Box 53, Folder 925)
  - Child Health Day, statement by Surge. Gen. Parran for OWI, News Sec. short-wave broadcast to foreign nations, May 1, 1943 (Box 53, Folder 926)
  - The Role of the U.S. Public Health Service in Venereal Disease Control. Published in Federal Probation, Vol. VII, No. 2, June 1943
  - Keep Fit For Victory - published in Courage magazine. Vol. IV, No. 1, 1943
  - Keeping Well In Wartime Published in This Week Magazine, 1942 (Box 53, Folder 927)
  - "Doctor Shortage Ahead" This Week Magazine, 1942 (Box 53, Folder 928)
  - Americans For the World of Tomorrow. For publication by Associated Press in feature page for women, August, 1942
  - "Labor's Stake in V.D. Control". Published in Textile Labor, June 1942 (Box 53, Folder 929)
  - Food Will Build a New America. Published in Nutrition News, December 1941 (Box 53, Folder 930)
  - Dear Father, Article by Dr. Parran which appeared in The Health Digest of the Iowa State Dept. of Health Annual Report, October 1940-1
  - Fitter Families, Parents' Magazine, November 1941 (Box 53, Folder 931)
  - "National Defense vs. Venereal Disease". Life Magazine, November (?) 1941 (Box 53, Folder 932)
  - What's New in Home Economics. Statement by Dr. Parran, September 1941
  - "Nutrition For National Defense". Published in The New Republic, June 9, 1941 (Box 53, Folder 933)
  - Childhood Education. "Need for Cooperation Among Community Health Agencies", February 1940 (Box 53, Folder 934)
  - "The Man I Want My Son To Be". Parents' Magazine, February 1940
  - "Recent Advances in the United States". Australia Public Health Notes, January 1940 (Box 53, Folder 935)
  - "100 Years of Medicine in the South. The Southern Planter, January 1940
  - The Union Signal. "A Message From the Surgeon General", January 6, 1940
  - National Education Association Journal. "Sex Education A Challenge", January 1940 (Box 53, Folder 936)
  - School Life. "The United States Public Health Service", November 1939
  - This Week. Sulfanilamide, Miracle or Menace, October 29, 1939 (Box 53, Folder 937)
  - Holy Cross Purple. "Health of the Nation", May 1939 (Box 53, Folder 938)
  - Child Health Day, 1939 (Box 53, Folder 939)
  - Future. "The Critical Years", January 1939 (Box 53, Folder 940)
  - New York Times. "Diphtheria", February 1939 (Box 53, Folder 941)
  - A Leading Health Problem. Rochester Commerce. N.Y., December 1938 (Box 53, Folder 942)
  - Social Work Today (symposium), December 1938 (Box 53, Folder 943)
  - Social Work Year Book for 1939. "Public Health", Mailed, July 29, 1938 (Box 53, Folder 944)
  - Why Mothers Die. "The Woman". Vol. I, No. 1, August 1938 (Box 54, Folder 945)
  - A World Safe For Mothers. Survey Midmonthly, April 1938
  - A Health Program For Rural America. An Interview With Mr. Streeter of "Farmer's Wife", March 1938
  - Modern Housing In Relation to Public Health. Green Belt Cooperator, 1938 (Box 54, Folder 946)
  - "Dr. Joseph Goldberger". The Jewish Advocate, December 31, 1939 (Box 54, Folder 947)
  - Industry Must do Something About Its Syphilis. Factory, September 1937 (Box 54, Folder 948)
  - "The American Druggist". How the Druggist Can Promote the V.D. Program, 1937 (Box 54, Folder 949)
  - "Let's Lift A Taboo". The Nation's Schools, September 1937
  - Syphilis Is Bad Business. Dun's Review, 1937 (Box 54, Folder 950)
  - We Can End His Sorrow by de Kruif Parran. Ladies Home Journal, August 1937
  - Rural Health Service Goes Forward Under the Social Security Act. Exten. Serv. Review, Agric. Dept., July 1937
  - Syphilis - Its Place in Industrial Medicine. Central of Georgia Magazine, July 1937 (Box 54, Folder 951)
  - Syphilis Can Be Stamped Out. Readers Digest, April 1937
  - "Responsibility Follows the Facts". The Attack on Syphilis. Published in Social Progress, 1937
  - Reduction in Maternal Mortality. The Clubwoman - GFWC., January 1957 (Box 54, Folder 952)
  - Avoid Contagious Diseases. Article published in "Life and Health". Takoma Park, Washington, D.C., December 1936
  - National Cost of Illness. The World Today., October 1936
  - Social Work Year Book, 1936 (Box 54, Folder 953)
  - Parran, Thomas Jr. M.D. Venereal Diseases. Social Work Year Book published in the spring of 1935, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 954)
  - Parran, Thomas Jr. M.D. Diphtheria Immunization. New York State Journal of Medicine, April 15, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 955)
  - Parran, Moore, Stekes, Cole, etc. Syphilis in Pregnancy. Cooperative Clinical Studies in the Treatment of Syphilis. Reprint No. 46. - Venereal Disease Information, March 1934 (Box 54, Folder 956)
  - Parran, Thomas Jr. M.D. Ancient and Modern Public Health. The Sanatorium Leaflet. Broome County TB Hospital, December 1932
  - Parran, Thomas Jr. M.D. Venereal Diseases, Control of. The Trained Nurse and Hospital Review, June 1928
  - Parran, Thomas Jr. M.D. How to Help the Farmer. Published in Illinois Health News, October 1926 (Box 54, Folder 957)
  - County Health Service. Public Health Reports, May 15, 1925
  - Parran, Thomas Jr. M.D. Syphilis Symposium. State Health Conference. Washington, D.C., 1951 (Box 54, Folder 958)
  - folder missing, not listed in finding aid (Box 54, Folder 960)
  - Syphilis Article. Survey Graphic Reader's Digest, 1936 (Box 54, Folder 961)
  - Article on Syphilis in Survey - Graphic Reader's Digest (Box 54, Folder 962)
  - Letters re Syphilis article. Survey - Graphic Reader's Digest, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 963)
- Organizations, Roughly 1938-1945; IX.
  - American College of Surgeons (Box 55, Folder 964)
  - American College of Physicians (Box 55, Folder 965)
  - American Dental Association (Box 55, Folder 966)
  - American Foundation Studies in Gov't, 1935-1936 (Box 55, Folder 967-970)
  - American Foundation for Tropical Med. (Box 56, Folder 971)
  - American Heart Association (Box 56, Folder 972)
  - American Hospital Association (Box 56, Folder 973)
  - American Legion (Box 56, Folder 974)
  - American Medical Association (Box 56, Folder 975)
  - The American Missourian Medical Society (Box 56, Folder 976)
  - American Pharmaceutical Association (Box 56, Folder 977)
  - A.P.H.A. - By Laws (Box 56, Folder 978)
  - American Public Health Association - General (Box 56, Folder 979)
  - A.P.H.A. Executive Board (Box 56, Folder 980)
  - A.P.H.A. Sedgwick Medal Committee (Box 56, Folder 981)
  - A.P.H.A. Comm. on Amer. Museum of Hygiene (Box 56, Folder 982)
  - A.P.H.A. Comm. on Laser Awards (Box 56, Folder 983)
  - American Public Welfare Association (Box 56, Folder 984)
  - A.S.H.A. Board of Directors, etc. (Box 57, Folder 985-986)
  - A.S.H.A. Anti-Syphilis Committee (Box 57, Folder 987)
  - A.S.H.A. Wm. Freeman Snow Award (Box 57, Folder 988)
  - Archives of Soc. Med. and Hygiene (Box 57, Folder 989)
  - Association of American Medical Colleges (Box 57, Folder 990)
  - Association of American Physicians (Box 57, Folder 991)
  - Assoc. of Military Surgeons of the U.S. (Box 57, Folder 992)
  - Boy Scouts of America (Box 57, Folder 993)
  - British Medical Association (Box 57, Folder 994)
  - Canadian Medical Association (Box 57, Folder 995)
  - Canadian Public Health Association (Box 57, Folder 996)
  - Commissioned Officers Association - USPHS (Box 57, Folder 997)
  - Committee of Physicians (Box 57, Folder 998)
  - The Commonwealth Fund (Box 58, Folder 999)
  - Cooperative Committee (Box 58, Folder 1000)
  - Association for the Aid of Crippled Children (Box 58, Folder 1001)
  - D.C. Medical Society (Box 58, Folder 1002)
  - D.C. Tuberculosis Assoc. (Box 58, Folder 1003)
  - Harvard College (Box 58, Folder 1004)
  - International College of Surgeons (Box 58, Folder 1005)
  - Jackson Laboratory (Box 58, Folder 1006)
  - Julius Rosenwald Fund (Box 58, Folder 1007)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 58, Folder 1008)
  - Meninger Foundation (Box 58, Folder 1009)
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company (Box 58, Folder 1010)
  - Military Medicine and Pharmacy (Box 58, Folder 1011)
  - Miscellaneous Organizations (Box 58, Folder 1012)
  - National Advisory Cancer Council (Box 58, Folder 1013)
  - National Board of Dental Examiners (Box 59, Folder 1014)
  - National Board of Medical Examiners (Box 59, Folder 1015-1016)
  - National Congress of Parents Teachers (Box 59, Folder 1017)
  - National Economic Social Planning Association (Box 59, Folder 1018)
  - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis-including The Little White (Box 59, Folder 1019)
  - National Nursing Council for War Service House, Warm Springs, GA (Box 60, Folder 1020)
  - National Organization for Public Health Nursing Pamphlet, 1948 (Box 60, Folder 1021)
  - National Physicians Committee (Box 60, Folder 1022)
  - National Research Council (Box 60, Folder 1023)
  - National Science Foundation Material (Box 60, Folder 1024)
  - National Tuberculosis Association (Box 60, Folder 1025)
  - New York Academy of Medicine (Box 60, Folder 1026)
  - New York State Medical Society (Box 60, Folder 1027)
  - Pan American Medical Association (Box 60, Folder 1028)
  - Henry Phipps Institute (Box 61, Folder 1029)
  - Safety council (Box 61, Folder 1030)
  - Science Service (Box 61, Folder 1031)
  - Southern Medical Association (Box 61, Folder 1032)
  - State Charities Aid Association (Box 61, Folder 1033-1034)
- Office of Foreign Relief and Rehabilitation Operations (O.F.R.R.O.), Mostly 1943; X.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Some folders are marked confidential. Contact the University Archivist for more information.
  - O.F.R.R.O. (Box 61, Folder 1035-1036)
  - O.F.R.R.O. (Box 62, Folder 1037)
  - Office of Foreign Relief. Sub-committee, 1943 (Box 62, Folder 1038)
  - O.F.R.R.O. Health Committee (Box 62, Folder 1039)
  - Medical Report on Tunisia (Box 62, Folder 1040)
  - United Nations Relief and Rehab. Admin. Proposed health program and organization. Part I - secret (Box 62, Folder 1041)
  - Report on Public Health in Greece (Box 62, Folder 1042)
  - Report on Public Health in Yugoslavia (Box 63, Folder 1043)
  - Report on Public Health in Rumania (Box 63, Folder 1044)
  - Medical and Sanitary Data on Norway (Box 63, Folder 1045)
  - O.F.R.R.O. (Box 63, Folder 1046)
  - Office of Foreign Relief. North Africa. (Box 63, Folder 1047)
  - Office of Foreign Agricultural Relations. U.S. Dept. of Agriculture (Box 63, Folder 1048)
- Vitamins Minerals, 1941-1943; XI.
  Some folders in this series are marked confidential. Contact the University Archivist for more information.
  - Biological (Box 63, Folder 1049)
  - Production and materials. Synthetic Vitamins, 1942 (Box 64, Folder 1050)
  - Riboflavin and the synthetic vitamins (Box 64, Folder 1051)
  - Vitamin C (citrus fruit content) (Box 64, Folder 1052)
  - Vitamin A (Fish oils) (Box 64, Folder 1053)
  - Vitamin Production - Totals (Box 64, Folder 1054)
  - Fats and Oils (Box 64, Folder 1055)
- Great Britain, XII.
  - British Food Mission (Box 64, Folder 1056)
  - Future Needs of Domestic, British and Unoccupied European Countries. Letter to President, April 8, 1941 (Box 64, Folder 1057)
  - Ministry of Health - General (Box 64, Folder 1058)
  - Nutrition in Great Britian (Box 64, Folder 1059)
  - Various Booklets on Air Raids, British cities at war, and information concerning casualties and evacuations. (Box 65, Folder 1060)
  - Correspondence (to G.B.) (Box 65, Folder 1061)
  - Air raids and shelters in G.B. (Box 65, Folder 1062)
  - Misc. G.B. (Air raid info., casualty, articles) (Box 65, Folder 1063)
  - Great Britain (Civil defense, post war plans) (Box 65, Folder 1064)
  - Supplemental report on Public Health, Medical and Sanitation aspects of civil defense in Great Britain (Box 65, Folder 1065)
  - Civil defense measures for the protection of children (in G.B.) (Box 66, Folder 1066)
  - Birmingham and Coventry Data (Box 66, Folder 1067)
  - British Medical Association (Box 66, Folder 1068)
  - Emergency Medical Service (Box 66, Folder 1069)
  - French Food Position (Box 66, Folder 1070)
  - London-School of Hygiene and Public Health (Box 66, Folder 1071)
  - London County Council (Box 66, Folder 1072)
  - Col. Harrison - V.D. (Box 66, Folder 1073)
  - London Water Supply (Box 66, Folder 1074)
  - Medical Research Council (Box 66, Folder 1075)
  - Ministry of Foods (Box 66, Folder 1076)
  - Willesdan and Ken. data (Box 66, Folder 1077)
  - British Food Mission. U.K. requirements from the U.S.A., 1941-1943 (Box 66, Folder 1078)
- United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, XIII.
  - UNRRA- Thomas Parran (Box 66, Folder 1079)
  - UNRRA- Scope of Activities and Financial Plan (Box 66, Folder 1080)
  - UNRRA- Standing technical Committee on Health - Correspondence (Box 66, Folder 1081)
  - UNRRA- Standing Technical Committee on Health (Box 66, Folder 1082)
  - UNRRA- Expert Commission on Quarantine (Box 66, Folder 1083)
  - UNRRA- Committee of Council for Europe (Box 66, Folder 1084)
  - UNRRA- Standing Tech. Sub. Comm. on Health for the Far East (Box 66, Folder 1085)
  - UNRRA Weekly Bulletins (Box 67, Folder 1086-1086)
  - United Nations Organization (mostly food and agriculture; War Peace aims, statements by United Nations leaders) (Box 67, Folder 1089)
  - UNRRA - Journals of the Council Montreal, Canada, Sept. 15-26, 1944 (Box 67, Folder 1090)
  - Correspondence on Montreal meeting (Box 68, Folder 1091)
  - Air Sanitary Convention (Box 68, Folder 1092)
  - International Sanitary Conventions (Box 68, Folder 1093)
  - No folder title given in finding aid (Box 68, Folder 1094)
  - Miscellaneous UNRRA Meetings- Montreal, Sept. 15-23, 1944 (Box 68, Folder 1096)
  - Miscellaneous UNRRA Meetings- Montreal - Oversized, Sept. 15-23, 1944 (Box 68, Folder 1097)
  - Statements on Health Medical Conditions - Atlantic City, New Jersey, November 10-December 1, 1943 (Box 68, Folder 1098)
  - Correspondence on Atlantic City meeting (Box 68, Folder 1099)
  - Nutrition Foundation, correspondence (Box 69, Folder 1100)
  - Nutrition Foundation minutes (Box 69, Folder 1101)
  - Nutrition Foundation misc. with published articles by Dr. Parran (Box 69, Folder 1102)
  - Nutrition Foundation reviews (Box 69, Folder 1103)
  - No title listed in finding aid (Box 69, Folder 1104)
- Rockefeller Foundation, XIV.
  - various programs, minutes, reports, misc. (Box 70, Folder 1105)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - The Education of Public Health Personnel (Box 70, Folder 1106)
  - Public Health Training - Medical Education (Box 70, Folder 1107)
  - General Education Board. Dr. Parran elected member of Board on, April 3, 1947 (Box 70, Folder 1108)
  - Minutes of Board of Trustees (Box 70, Folder 1109)
  - Dockets - Annual meetings (Box 70, Folder 1110-1111)
  - Financial Reports (Box 71, Folder 1112-1114)
  - Confidential monthly reports for Trustees (Box 72, Folder 1115-1116)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Comm. reports (Box 72, Folder 1117-1118)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - International Health Division minutes, 1944 (Box 73, Folder 1119-1120)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation - International Health Div. General correspondence (Box 73, Folder 1121)
- St. John's College, XV.
  - Minutes - Board of Governors, St. John's College (Box 73, Folder 1122)
  - St. John's College - Budget and Finance (Box 74, Folder 1123)
  - Catalogs and various publications and memorabilia of St. John's College (Box 74, Folder 1124)
- Milbank Memorial Fund, XVI.
  - Milbank Memorial Fund- Correspondence (Box 74, Folder 1125)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund- Annual conferences (Box 74, Folder 1126)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund- Minutes (Box 74, Folder 1127)
  - Syphilis control in Scandinavian countries (Box 74, Folder 1128)
  - Norway (Box 74, Folder 1129)
  - Sweden (Box 74, Folder 1130)
  - London County Council (misc. reprints) (Box 74, Folder 1131)
  - London - Wales - England (Box 74, Folder 1132)
  - General (Box 74, Folder 1133)
  - Pan American Sanitary Organization (Box 75, Folder 1134)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - Public Health As An International Problem. A.P.H.A., October 3, 1944 (Box 75, Folder 1135)
  - Various World Health Organization Publications (Box 76, Folder 1136)
  - U.S. Delegation Material - (State Dept.) First Session (Box 76, Folder 1137)
  - World Health Assembly - Geneva (Box 76, Folder 1138)
  - International Health Conference - N.Y., 1946 (Box 76, Folder 1139)
  - UNRRA - WHO Residual Funds (Box 76, Folder 1140)
  - International Children's Emergency Fund, miscellaneous (Box 76, Folder 1141)
  - Report of survey mission to the far east. Terms of reference (Box 76, Folder 1142)
  - Mexico City - Pan American Sanitary Organization, October 8-12, 1948 (Box 77, Folder 1143)
  - Miscellaneous - Geneva Meeting, WHO, June 24-July 24, 1948 (Box 77, Folder 1144)
  - Data by country - survey mission - Far East (Box 77, Folder 1145)
  - W.H.O., Travel, expenses, etc (Box 77, Folder 1146)
  - Misc. (World Health) (Box 77, Folder 1147)
- Food and Agricultural Organization - United Nations, XVII.
  - Food and Agriculture Organization (Box 78, Folder 1148)
  - United Nations Conference on International Organization, San Francisco, Calif., June 25, 1945 (Box 78, Folder 1149)
  - Interim Commission - Food Agric. Org. (Box 78, Folder 1150)
  - F.O.A. misc., United Nations Relief Rehabilitation Administration, misc. - early material (Box 78, Folder 1151)
  - Hot Springs, Va. Meeting, FAO, 1943 (Box 78, Folder 1152)
  - Quebec meeting, FAO, 1945 (Box 78, Folder 1153)
  - Meeting in Copenhagen, FAO, 1946 (Box 79, Folder 1154)
  - Material on B.C.G. (a vaccination for tuberculosis) (Box 79, Folder 1155)
  - Health survey in Denmark, 1926 (Box 79, Folder 1156)
- Pre-University of Pittsburgh, XVIII.
  - Statistical data (pertaining to medical cost) (Box 79, Folder 1157)
  - University of Pittsburgh - general correspondence (Box 79, Folder 1158)
  - R.S. Boughton (Univ. of Pgh. concerning Mellon Educ. Fund) (Box 79, Folder 1159)
  - Clippings pertaining to new Public Health School at Univ. of Pgh. (Box 79, Folder 1159-A)
  - Congratulatory letters - Univ. of Pgh., Public Health School (Box 79, Folder 1159-B)
- Dr. Parran (University of Pittsburgh) A-Z, 1948-1961; XIX.
  - A-miscellaneous (Box 80, Folder 1160)
  - Air Pollution, literature in re. (Box 80, Folder 1161)
  - "Alaska's Health: A Survey Report" (Box 80, Folder 1162)
  - Alpha Omega Alpha Honor Medical Society (The Pharos) (Box 80, Folder 1163)